Welcome back to the show, John Kuryaku.
>> Good to see you again.
>> You, too. It's always a pleasure. You're
an amazing storyteller uh and guest. And
uh we want to talk to you about Epstein.
>> Are you still talking about Jeffrey
Epstein? This guy's been talked about
for years. You're asking, "We have
Texas, we have this, we have all of the
things." And are people still talking
about this guy? this creep.
That is unbelievable.
Do you want to waste the time and do you
feel like answering?
>> I I don't mind answering.
>> I mean, I can't believe you're asking a
question on Epstein at a time like this
where we're having some of the greatest
success and and also tragedy with what
happened in Texas. It just seems uh like
a desecration. But you go ahead.
>> How do you like that?
>> Yeah. Big change from what he was saying
before.
>> We're going to get to the bottom of it.
He's going to release all the documents,
the He's going to release the videos and
then you're still talking about this,
>> right? Yeah. And he's hiding behind the
tragedy in Texas. Um, so what are your
thoughts? What what happened? I mean, I
I did see that on both uh Pierce Morgan
and on Fox News, you said that you feel
material was probably destroyed. Can you
elaborate on that and why that?
>> Sure. at the CIA.
Even though there are laws like the the
Federal Records Act, which specifically
says you cannot destroy documents,
they destroy documents all the time. I
mean MK Ultra even after even after
Congress specifically told the director
of central intelligence that he had to
preserve the MK Ultra documents, he went
back to headquarters and they destroyed
80% of the tens of thousands of pages of
documents that they had on MK Ultra. So
now, you know, we don't really know what
is true and what's not true about MK
Ultra because of of the cover up,
>> right? Same same thing at the CIA with
the torture videos. As soon as word
leaked out that there were videos of Abu
Zuba and Khalik Muhammad being tortured,
Harriet Meyers, who was the White House
counsel at the time in the in the George
uh W. Bush presidency, Harriet Meyer
specifically told Jose Rodriguez, the
deputy director for operations at the
CIA and Gina Haspel, "Don't destroy the
tapes." And Gina Haspel put them in an
industrial grinder and destroyed them.
>> Right?
>> So, you know, why would we think that
the FBI would be any different,
especially when it comes to allegations
that some of the most powerful and some
of the wealthiest men in the world are
implicated in this scandal. Some of the
most powerful politicians in the world
may be implicated in this scandal,
right?
>> So, I could absolutely see the FBI
destroying documents and we could
speculate as to what the reason would
be. It could be just cash on the
barrelhead.
>> You know, it may that may be it may be
as simple as that. It may be that
there's more to this so-called deep
state than people think there is. So
yeah, I I don't I don't trust that
just like like this revelation like oh
my goodness, it turns out there are no
documents, there are no dossas, there
are no videos except for child porn.
Come on, man. Going back to the 1990s
and you couldn't find anything.
>> Yeah, it's pretty implausible.
>> I don't buy it.
>> Right. I mean, it it is just one of the
latest examples of Trump and his
administration
uh promising to take things on, ranging
from, you know, the deep state to
draining the the swamp to uh the
industrial military-industrial complex
and then once they're in power, they
don't. Or being uh America firsters and
then saying ridiculous things about
Israel. I mean, everyone from Cash Patel
to Tammy Bruce making statements that
are embarrassingly
uh subordinate to Israel. So, I mean,
does this is this just because Trump is
really good at saying the right things?
He I mean, I always I always think of
him kind of like as a stand-up comedian.
Uh he he knows how to work a crowd. He
knows how to get a response from people.
Um but then in terms of actual policy,
he doesn't seem to to line up.
>> I think that he's really not terribly
interested in policy. I don't think he
ever has been. And certainly we've had
other presidents that weren't interested
in policy, but yeah, I think that he
says what happened whatever happens to
be, you know, at at the top of his mind
and um and whether he ends up
contradicting himself later or not, he
doesn't really care. I think that
ideologically
he's a Zionist and I think he's so much
so that he's unwilling to bend. When I
was serving in Bahrain, the Amir of
Bahrain said something that has always
stuck in my mind. He said, "The last
American president to give the Arabs a
fair shake was George HW Bush."
>> Right?
>> And every president since then has just
been in the pay of the Israelis directly
or indirectly. And the Arabs don't even
pretend to think that they're going to
get a fair shake, but we're seeing it in
spades um in this administration.
>> Yeah, I it's interesting you said that
cuz I I think that Trump is and this is
why I thought there was like a very
small chance that he'd be better than
Biden because I think that Trump maybe
he's a Zionist, but I think his Zionism
is a lot less strong, a lot weaker than
u Biden's. Like who was more in
generally I think Biden is more of an
ideologue than Trump. I mean, I think
Trump is pretty not, you know,
ideological, much more opportunistic.
>> Definitely a populist. Yep.
>> Yeah. I mean, full of it, but I think
just in general, you know, what the
bottom line for him is real estate, uh,
more than it is any any kind of
ideology. But, um, as someone who was in
the CIA, what did you observe about the
relationship between the United States
and Israel? Oh, more than any other
relationship that we have with any other
country in the world, the relationship
is dictated on Capitol Hill.
Not at the White House, but on Capitol
Hill. I I was I I was on a podcast
earlier today. We were talking about
this exact issue. And I said I said when
I when I went to the Senate Foreign
Relations Committee in 2009, I was the
senior investigator there working for
John Kerry. I had been in the job like a
day or two days and these lobbyists came
by. It was a parade of lobbyists, right?
Every cause, every lobbyist comes
through at one time or another, but this
this was the first group of lobbyists.
And they came to the office and they
said, "Hey,
congratulations.
So great to have you on the Senate
Foreign Relations Committee. we're from
Apac and we want to bring you on an all
expenses paid trip to the Holy Land. I
was like, "Oh, thank you. No, no, thank
you."
Oh, we we have a tour already laid out.
We're going to take you to all the
Christians Christian holy sites and
you're going to see what a first world
country we are and we are America's
greatest ally and we're the only
democracy in the Middle East. I was
like, "No, thank you. Thank you." Well,
there were there were a bunch of people
who went. I didn't go. I I even was a
little bit rude and I said, "Look, if I
want to go to Israel, I'm going to pay
for my own trip to Israel, but I I don't
want you you guys to pay for a trip to
Israel." And I didn't go,
>> but others went. Well, it turns out they
do this with literally every staff for
every congressman, 435 of them in the
House and a hundred of them in the
Senate. That is money well spent. And
then they contribute millions upon
millions of dollars to um campaigns,
congressional campaigns mostly. And man,
if you look at Israel cockeyed, they'll
primary you,
>> right? And so they've gotten to the
point or they've gotten us to the point
where people are so afraid to say
anything about Israel, anything, because
if you say if if there's any criticism
at all, no matter how mild, even if the
criticism is of Benjamin Netanyahu as a
politician,
you're anti-Semitic. And then you've got
to dig yourself out of that hole.
>> Yeah. So most most elected officials,
they they just don't want to deal with
it, so they just go along.
>> And what can you tell us about the
relationship between Israeli and US
intelligence?
>> It is um not close on a uh on a personal
level. Uh we never liked Mossad. They
don't like us. Um the Israelis spy on
the United States and uh they deny and
deny and deny. In fact, I was on Pierce
Morgan a couple of weeks ago debating oh
my god Alan Dersowitz. I was with Scott
Horton and we were we were debating Alan
Dersowitz and uh Danny,
what was his name? Yalon. He was the
former head of Mossad general.
And I said
the Israeli spy on the United States.
And he said no, no, no, that's not true.
when the Americans caught uh uh Jonathan
Pard in 1995, we stopped spying on the
United States. And I said, "With all due
respect, General, that's not true
because I didn't start at the CIA until
1990." and the chief of security warned
us that there were two uh Israeli
intelligence officers assigned to the
Israeli embassy in Washington and
187 undeclared Israeli intelligence
officers spread all across the United
States stealing American secrets after
having penetrated our defense
contractors. So, with all due respect,
you're dissembling here the Israeli spy
on the United States. What do you think
of the way that uh Trump has gone from
being America first to uh someone who is
a pretty sickopantic to BB? Now, to be
fair, it's a kind of circle jerk uh
where they both um really suck up to
each other. And of course, you have uh
Netanyahu, I mean, hilariously, uh
nominating Donald Trump for a Nobel
Peace Nobel Peace Prize.
>> Yeah. Uh what do you think of this?
>> Well, circle jerk is the best way to say
it, actually.
I I won't get into the specifics of what
a circle jerk is. People can Google it.
But
>> when Trump dropped the fbomb, what was
it, a week ago, two weeks ago, that was
specifically meant for Netanyahu.
>> Okay?
>> Because Trump wanted his ceasefire
between the Israelis and the Iranians.
And Netanyahu was like, "Well, you know,
maybe we're going to launch one more.
Well, just one more barrage." And then
he's like, you know, cut it the out
or whatever it was. He said,
>> "Yeah,
>> they don't know what the they're
doing." I think is what he said. That
was specifically meant for Netanyahu
because the Iranians only react. They
don't they don't proactively attack
Israel.
>> Right. Despite the way the media covers
it.
>> Correct. And so
that little there was just that little
blip for a day and then it was all
passed. I was driving um to Capitol Hill
last night. You couldn't turn left on on
17th Street. you couldn't turn left on
15th Street. Pennsylvania Avenue was
closed. I'm like, what the is going
on here? Like, are they just going to
shut down the city? I said, why is it
like this? And the Uber driver said,
BB's in town. Nobody's moving anywhere
in Washington.
>> And then I I talked to a a a contact of
mine today who happens to be doing some
work for the Israeli embassy, and he
said that Netanyahu is staying for a
week. This isn't just an in-n-out visit
where he just meets with the president,
shake hands, does a photo op, and
leaves. He's here all week. That gives
you an idea of how close this
relationship is.
>> I think Netanyahu was sick and tired of
Joe Biden and the Democrats, even though
Biden and the Democrats gave them
literally everything they wanted, but
he's far more comfortable with Donald
Trump because I think he's able to manip
to manipulate Donald Trump.
>> I mean, maybe both of them, right?
Wasn't he able? Isn't that something?
Isn't that kind of like the bipartisan
uh a bipartisan phenomenon?
>> It really is. It really is. You know,
Katie, if I could add one thing, too.
Years ago, 2008 to 2012.
I'm I'm almost embarrassed to say this.
I was an adjunct professor of uh
intelligence studies at Liberty
University, which was Jerry Fwell's
evangelical Christian Yes. University.
to make it even worse in the Jesse Helm
School of Government.
>> Oh my gosh. Wow.
>> Okay. Yeah. And when they called me to
offer me this job, I said, "Why would
you guys call me?" I said, "We we
probably disagree on 99% of the issues.
Why me?" And without missing a beat, the
dean said, "Because torture is not
Christian."
>> Ah, interesting.
>> And I said, "Okay, I'll take it." And I
ended up really truly enjoying my time
there.
>> Nice guys. We disagreed on everything,
>> right?
>> But genuinely nice people.
>> I am still, for reasons that are unclear
to me, on the Liberty University list
served.
And every once in a while, I just can't
remain silent. And so I have to crack on
them.
They are so
what what word can I use? They are
so pro-Israel,
>> right,
>> as to be fanatical about it. And they
can't even explain to you why they're so
pro- Israel. I mean, deep down, I know
what it is. It's because they want all
the Jews to return to Israel so that the
Messiah can come and Armageddon and the
apocalypse and, you know, that whole
thing, which is all, you know, fantasy,
>> right? But um I crack on them all the
time and I say St. Borfidio's Church in
Gaza, the oldest continually operating
Christian church on earth.
And the Israelis bomb it to rubble and
kill everybody inside. By the way, every
one of them was either a woman or a
child. And you guys don't say anything
about that,
>> right? You don't say anything that
they're literally wiping out the
Palestinian Christian community in the
West Bank after having already wiped it
out in Gaza. You guys don't say a word.
But God forbid somebody should criticize
Benjamin Netanyahu. All of a sudden,
we're anti-Semitic.
>> I said, "You guys are anti-Christian
because you've literally not lifted a
finger to help Palestine's Christians.
Christians who have been there for 2,000
years.
2,000 years. You don't say a word about
that. And then nobody says anything.
>> Yeah. And of course, uh it's also not
very Christian to support genocide.
>> No.
>> And it's also not very pro I mean, we
know this as you said, it's it's totally
opportunistic and transactional. Uh they
they are not friends of the Jews. I mean
that utilize us and like you mentioned.
So we'll all go back. I think 400 of us
get to survive and the rest burn for all
eternity.
>> That's exactly right. That Yeah, they
make it seem like in fact, you know
what? There was a scene in the Sopranos
about exactly that. That what that
somebody said, well, they're great
friends of Israel. And then Hesh said,
"Oh, don't let that fool you. They only
like Israel because they want us to all
go back there so they can kill us all."
>> Wow.
>> And that's really what it comes down to.
>> I did not know that. I'm gonna have to
watch that now. Yeah. So, on Fox News um
with Marie Bartomo, Netanyahu made some
comments about how he has quote broken
the Iran access end quote and helped
usher in a new Middle East. What are
your reactions to this claim? As someone
who has worked extensively in the region
and written about Iran before, is there
any uh validity to his claims?
>> I hate to say yes. Um, I think it's
temporary because people aren't stupid
and the world is constantly changing and
so the Iranians and the Lebanese and
probably the Palestinians will figure
something out. But if you look at just
the last 6 months,
well the last eight months, he
decapitated Hzbalah.
Decapitated it for for all intents and
purposes. It's it it has ceased to
exist. It's going to come back.
>> Yeah.
>> But right now it's it's nothing.
>> He essentially working with the Turks
overthrew Bashar al-Assad.
>> I'm no supporter of Bashar al-Assad, but
but I always said
if you're concerned about Christian
communities, Bashar al-Assad was the
only thing standing between the
Christian communities and complete
annihilation.
>> Yeah.
Uh, so Assad's gone, too. And Gaza's
been just, you know, vaporized. It's
almost, it's almost gone in and of
itself. So, for the time being, yeah,
he's broken the Iranian access. He still
has the Houthies to worry about, but
they're more of a little, you know,
pimple on the butt of the Israeli body
politic than they are a real threat to
anything. And I wouldn't be surprised if
they start, you know, bombarding the
Houthies. But the Houthies are so poor
and they have so little. I mean, how
many million dollar bombs are you going
to spend to blow up $10,000 drones?
Really, is it worth it?
>> Um, when when the Israelis
u implemented this operation against
Hezbollah with the pagers, the pagers
and the cell phones.
>> My phone ran off rang off the hook with
former agency friends like, "What do you
think about this?" And I said, "Holy
this is like on the one hand, it's
a it's a crime against humanity or a war
crime, depending on your your position."
Clearly, innocent civilians, including
children, were hurt or killed because
these things just arbitrarily blew up.
And, you know, we saw reports of people
having taken their phones out of their
pockets and they put it on the table so
they could have dinner with their
families and it blew up and killed the
nine-year-old girl
>> that it was next to.
So yeah, war crime,
but absolutely brilliant from an
intelligence operations perspective.
Imagine the moving parts that went into
an operation like this where you've got
to control literally everything from the
point of manufacturing
through the supply chain across half the
globe and then into the hands of the
consumer.
Absolutely incredible. I don't know if
we'll ever be able to figure out how
they pulled this off,
>> right?
>> And then, you know, working with the
Turks, who the Israelis either love or
hate, depending on what day of the week
it happens to be, they came to this
agreement that if you help us screw
Assad, we'll help you screw the Kurds.
And the Turks said, "Sounds good to us."
Next thing you know, the Assad family
runs off to Moscow. Bashar comes back
for a week, fills the plane with riches,
and then he runs off to Moscow.
>> Right.
>> So, these the Israelis have been very
busy, and they've been very successful
at it. For better or for worse,
>> for worse, I would say. Um,
>> but, you know, it's interesting because
you have some people who say, "Oh, that
was not I mean, obviously there's
there's a lot of people say it's
technically technologically brilliant."
But then you have people saying, "Oh, it
was targeted. It wasn't targeted at
all." as you just pointed out, it killed
it.
>> Wasn't targeted.
>> Yeah. And um you know, Leon Petta, who's
not exactly a peace, he said it was an
act of terrorism.
>> Yeah. I that that shocked me because I
would have expected the likes of Leon
Petta to say, you know, bravo Mossad. Oh
my god, we should all aspire to do
things like that. But even he said it
was an act of terrorism, which it was,
>> right?
>> It was. So going back to uh Epstein,
what is the relationship between Epstein
and Israel? And what do we know about uh
who was uh on the plane uh who engaged
in, you know, basically sex crimes?
>> And to hear the rest of the interview,
please go to usefulspodcast.com.
[Music]